in this episode i'm going to show you how to
build a flyout effect on the GrandMA 3 software
from scratch last episode we used a macro to load
some predefined effects we have them right here if
you missed that one that's episode 10 you can find
that on our playlist but in this episode i think
we should try to build a fly out effect from
scratch to better understand what is happening
when you do so so first of all let's open our
phaser editor we go into our common window in
here and add the phaser editor i'm gonna make this
a little bit smaller because we need another step
bar which we find down here right here this is
the different programming steps we can use when
we program the phaser to build our flyout effect
we need two steps the first step is dimmer at zero
and the first position the next step is dimmer
at full and the second position so let's start
by building the first one we choose all our vipers
we go down into dimmer and we set the dimmer value
at zero for step one then we go into step number
two and we select our dimmer again we set it to
full now the dimmer effect starts to pulsate we go
back into step number one and deselect step number
two and we select our position down here and we
press the button down here and we find our presets
and say okay our position number one i think
i'll choose my position number one for that
one so right now it goes into position number one
then we select step two and we deselect step one
we go back into pen and tilt and we select our
roof position now the effect starts moving but
it doesn't really look like a fly out yet because
we have to edit some some different things in here
you can see the pan we can see the tilt here and
we can see the dimmer values up here we need to
have a different dimmer curve on the dimmer so
we deselect the pen and we deselect the tilt
and we go into this one down here and we select
a hard cut for the dimmer effect so right now it
turns it snaps on and it snaps off so
basically now we already built a cool flyout
so we need to space it out a little bit so we
select everything again and then we go into our
face down here and we select zero through
360 for instance and then you can see a nice
flyout so that's how easy it is to build a flyout
effect on the GrandMA 3 software you can start
playing with the phase you can do all kinds of
things we haven't touched GrandMA 3 MAtricks yet in
this tutorial series but there you can randomize
the the way it moves when it applies the phase let
me just show you if i go into matrix here and i go
into shuffle and i just give it some random value
and i apply the phase again you can see it
randomizes the flyout so as you can see it's quite
easy to build a flyout effect from scratch please
give the video a like if you learned something and
and subscribe to the channel if you don't want to
miss any future episodes see you next time bye bye